Hey.
嘿。
What's taking so long?
什么事要花这么长时间？
I never got my fries.
我从来没有得到过我的薯条。
Why doesn't my father love me?
为什么我的父亲不爱我？
[customers complaining]
【顾客投诉】
- Hey, Squidward.
- Quit it.
- 嘿，章鱼哥。
- 退出吧。
- Hey, Squidward.
- Quit it.
- 嘿，章鱼哥。
- 退出吧。
- Hey, Squidward.
- Quit it!
- 嘿，章鱼哥。
- 戒掉吧！
Mr. Squidward, clean up
in the head.
章鱼哥先生，清理干净
在头脑中。
Hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。
Also, clean up here.
还有，把这里打扫干净。
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
Hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。
I said clean up.
我说清理。
- Squidward!
- Squidward.
- 章鱼哥！
- 章鱼哥。
Hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。
Hey, Squidward. Hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。嘿，章鱼哥。
- Squidward!
- Hey, Squidward, Squidward,
- 章鱼哥！
- 嘿，章鱼哥，章鱼哥，
hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。
Oh, no...
哦，不...
Don't just lay there.
Clean up. Clean up. Clean up!
别只是躺在那里。
清理。清理。清理！
Aah!
啊啊！
It was just a dream.
这只是一个梦。
Just a horrible, realistic,
totally on point dream.
只是一个可怕的、现实的、
完全符合梦想。
Oh, I can't believe
I'm dreaming about work
哦，我不敢相信
我梦见工作
when there's so many
more interesting things
当有这么多的时候
更多有趣的事情
I could be doing.
我可以做。
Just look at
my unfinished painting.
看看
我未完成的画。
And my unfinished symphony.
还有我未完成的交响曲。
And my uneaten strudel.
还有我没吃过的馅饼。
My strudel!
我的馅饼！
Just tasted like pie to me.
对我来说尝起来就像馅饼。
It's a strudel, you barbarian.
这是馅饼，你这个野蛮人。
Just look at those
pastry layers.
看看那些
糕点层。
- Oh, yeah.
- Ohh...
- 哦，是的。
- 哦...
I just woke up and the day's
already a disaster.
我刚刚醒来，这一天
已经是一场灾难了。
I can't face
the Krusty Krab today.
我无法面对
今天的蟹堡王。
I am staying home and diving
into an ocean of Squidward.
我呆在家里潜水
进入章鱼哥的海洋。
[jungle sounds]
[丛林的声音]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Ahh...
啊...
What the...
什么...
Oh... [muttering]
哦...[低语]
Any more of that layer pie?
还有那层馅饼吗？
Get out!
出去！
Now to get rid of
the other monkey on my back.
现在要摆脱
我背上的另一只猴子。
[ah-ah-ahem]
[啊啊啊咳]
[clearing throat]
[清嗓子]
Krusty Krab.
蟹堡王。
[coughing]
[咳嗽]
Oh, Mr. Krabs, it's...
[gagging, coughing]
噢，蟹老板，这是……
[作呕，咳嗽]
Squidward.
章鱼哥。
Mr. Squidward?
章鱼哥先生？
What are you doing on the phone?
你在打电话做什么？
You should be working.
- [hacking]
你应该工作了。
- [黑客攻击]
Can't work.
Too...[hacking] sick.
无法工作。
太……[黑客]生病了。
Ah-choo!
啊呼！
You do sound pretty bad.
你听起来确实很糟糕。
Are you sure
you're too sick to work?
你确定吗
你病得太重了，无法工作吗？
Ha ha.
I mean, I mean...[coughing]
哈哈。
我是说，我是说……[咳嗽]
positive.
积极的。
Hmm...
唔...
Too sick, hey?
太有病了吧？
Oh, I got the cure
for what ails you.
哦，我找到了解药
是什么让你不舒服。
Well, you just rest up,
Mr. Squidward.
那你就好好休息吧
章鱼哥先生。
I'll take care of everything.
我会处理好一切。
Okay, bye, talk to you...
好吧，再见，再跟你聊聊……
I mean, I mean... [hacking]
我的意思是，我的意思是... [黑客攻击]
[hoarsely]
Bye!
[沙哑]
再见！
No one fake sick on Mr. Krabs
and gets away with it.
没有人对蟹老板假装生病
并侥幸逃脱。
No work for me today.
今天我没有工作。
Mr. Squidward gets to play.
No customers for me to fear.
章鱼哥先生开始玩了。
没有顾客让我害怕。
SpongeBob can take a long
walk along a very sharp pier.
海绵宝宝可能需要很长时间
沿着一个非常陡峭的码头走。
[knock on door]
Huh?
[敲门]
啊？
Oh. That must be
the crudité I ordered.
哦。那一定是
我点的生菜。
Well... oh!
嗯……哦！
Oh, Mr. Krabs.
I didn't see you there.
哦，蟹老板。
我在那儿没看到你。
How thoughtful of you to
visit me in my weakened state.
你想得多么周到
在我虚弱的状态下拜访我。
Oh, think nothing of it,
Mr. Squidward.
哦，别想了，
章鱼哥先生。
You sounded so bad on the phone
I rushed right over
你在电话里的声音听起来很糟糕
我立刻冲了过去
to make sure you were
taking good care of yourself.
确保你是
照顾好自己。
Well, I wouldn't want
to infect anyone,
好吧，我不想
感染任何人，
so you should probably go now.
所以你也许应该现在就走。
Oh, you are in no condition
to be alone.
哦，你没状态
独自一人。
That's why I brought
you some help.
这就是为什么我带来了
你帮忙吧。
Take one of these
and call me in the morning.
采取其中之一
早上给我打电话。
The doctor is in.
医生进来了。
Oh...
哦...
Swaddle, swaddle, swaddle.
襁褓，襁褓，襁褓。
Hush-aby now,
don't strain yourself.
现在安静点，
不要让自己太紧张。
Really, Mr. Krabs,
this isn't necessary.
真的，蟹老板先生，
这是没有必要的。
Of course it is.
当然是。
If I find out you were faking it
如果我发现你是假的
just to get out of work,
I'd have to fire you.
只是为了摆脱工作，
我不得不解雇你。
No faking here.
No, I'm really... [cough] sick.
这里没有造假。
不，我真的……[咳嗽]病了。
Okay, back to the swaddling.
好吧，回到襁褓中。
Aw!
噢！
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Oh, yes. I like that.
哦是的。我喜欢这样。
Uh-huh, uh-huh.
Indeed.
嗯嗯，嗯嗯。
的确。
[gasps]
[喘气]
Squidward!
You're overexerting yourself.
章鱼哥！
你太用力了。
Now you just rest that sick
little body of yours
现在你就好好休息吧
你小小的身体
while SpongeBob finishes up
your self-portrait for you.
当海绵宝宝结束时
你的自画像。
- But... but... but...
- Ha ha!
- 但是...但是...但是...
- 哈哈！
La la la la!
啦啦啦啦！
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah. Done.
哦，是啊，哦，是啊。完毕。
In my imagination,
you're a helpless little baby.
在我的想象中，
你是一个无助的小婴儿。
Gee, you're sicker
than I thought.
哎呀，你病得更重了
比我想象的要多。
[Squidward vomiting]
【鱿鱼呕吐】
Eh...
呃……
Now just forget
that yellow nuisance
现在只是忘记
那个黄色的麻烦
and lose yourself in music.
并在音乐中迷失自我。
♪
- Squidward!
- 章鱼哥！
You shouldn't be wasting your
breath in your weakened state.
你不应该浪费你的
在你虚弱的状态下呼吸。
Let me blow
the clarinet for you.
让我吹
为你准备的单簧管。
No, no, don't touch my...
♪ ♪
不，不，别碰我的……
Don't touch my...
别碰我的...
Hmm? Bleh.
唔？布莱赫。
[musical inhale]
[音乐吸气]
[whimpering]
[呜咽]
Ah. The perfect strudel will
make everything all right.
啊。完美的果馅卷将
让一切都好起来。
- Oh, Squidward.
- Oh...
-哦，章鱼哥。
- 哦...
Time to take your temperature.
是时候量体温了。
Get that thing away from my...
把那东西从我的身边拿开……
Ooh! 98.6. Oh, Squidward,
you're all better.
哦！ 98.6。哦，章鱼哥，
你们都好多了。
I'm so happy we can both go
to the Krusty Krab now.
我很高兴我们可以一起走
现在去蟹堡吧。
What? No!
什么？不！
Give me that thing.
You must've read it wrong.
把那个东西给我。
你一定是读错了。
Oh, hey.
What's that over there?
哦，嘿。
那边是什么？
Oh cool. A wall.
哦，酷。一堵墙。
So smooth.
如此顺利。
Well, that was fun.
嗯，那很有趣。
Now, let's check that
thermometer again, shall we?
现在，让我们检查一下
再来一次温度计，好吗？
Here you go.
干得好。
Yikes. A fever.
哎呀。发烧了。
Squidward, we got
to cool you off.
章鱼哥，我们得到了
让你冷静下来。
Stop.
停止。
You're right,
you need it even colder.
你说得对，
你需要更冷的温度。
[shrieking, whimpering]
[尖叫，呜咽]
Thank you.
谢谢。
- Oh, boy.
- There, all better?
- 哦，男孩。
- 怎么样，好些了吗？
N-no, you buffoon.
不——不，你这个小丑。
You're right, Squidward.
你是对的，章鱼哥。
I have been... buffoon.
我一直是……小丑。
W-w-what?
什、什、什么？
I've been treating the symptoms
我一直在治疗症状
instead of the sickness.
而不是疾病。
Stay away from me
with that thing.
离我远点
与那件事。
But we have to figure out
但我们必须弄清楚
what you have
so we can treat it.
你有什么
这样我们就可以治疗它。
No, uh, I already know
what I have.
不，呃，我已经知道了
我有什么。
It's, uh, acute...
这，呃，很尖锐……
spotting... sclorboritis.
发现... 菌毛炎。
Acute spotting sclorboritis?
急性点状菌毛炎？
I never heard of that one.
Better look it up.
我从来没有听说过那个。
最好查一下。
Ah-choo, ah-choo, ah-choo!
啊，啊，啊，啊！
Oh, you're getting worse!
哎呀，你越来越坏了！
We've got to find a cure fast.
我们必须尽快找到治疗方法。
I found it. Here it is.
我找到了。这里是。
- You did?
- Yup.
- 你做到了？
- 是的。
And the cure
seems pretty simple.
还有治愈方法
看起来很简单。
See?
看？
Uh... uh, wait...
呃……呃，等等……
wait, did I say acute
spotting sclorboritis?
等等，我说的是急性吗
发现毛球炎？
No, no, I must've meant...
plerkington's syndrome.
不不不，我的意思一定是……
普勒金顿综合症。
Found it. Now, let's get
to the curing, shall we?
找到了。现在，让我们得到
去治愈，好吗？
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
Aah!
啊啊！
♪ ♪
♪♪
Huh?
啊？
[Squidward gagging]
[章鱼哥作呕]
- Are we done?
- Don't be silly.
- 我们完成了吗？
- 别傻了。
We've just begun.
我们才刚刚开始。
Aah!
啊啊！
[ringing]
[铃声]
Tentacles residence.
SpongeBob speaking.
触手居住地。
海绵宝宝在说话。
Hello, me boy-o.
你好，我的孩子。
How's the patient?
- Better. I'm all better.
病人怎么样了？
- 更好的。我好多了。
Please, just let me
go back to work.
请让我
回去工作吧。
Oh, nonsense.
You still look so sick.
哦，废话。
你看起来还是那么病态。
Better step up the cure,
SpongeBob.
更好地加强治疗，
海绵宝宝。
Whatever you say Mr. Krabs.
不管你说什么，蟹老板。
Open wide.
敞开。
You will not get that
anywhere near my mouth.
你不会明白的
靠近我嘴的任何地方。
Ha ha ha ha!
Guess again.
哈哈哈哈！
再猜一下。
Aah!
啊！
So, the book told me
to stretch his nose,
所以，这本书告诉我
伸展他的鼻子，
shock him with a jellyfish,
and then I scraped his lungs
用水母吓他一跳，
然后我刮了他的肺
and cleaned them out
with a toxic eating urchin.
并清理掉它们
与有毒的食海胆。
Hoo hoo hoo hoo.
Hee he hee hee!
呼呼呼呼。
嘿嘿嘿嘿！
Priceless.
无价。
Well, Mr. Squidward.
好吧，章鱼哥先生。
Feeling better
after your sick day?
感觉好多了
病假后？
You might say that.
你可能会这么说。
[gasps] He's glorious.
[喘气]他很光荣。
That's right, I used to be
sick of everything,
没错，我曾经也是
厌倦了一切，
but I'm not sick anymore.
但我不再生病了。
I've been plagued by toxins
and stress built up
我一直被毒素困扰
和压力的积累
over the years at this job,
多年来从事这份工作，
but SpongeBob washed those away.
但海绵宝宝把它们洗掉了。
[squeals]
[尖叫声]
Now, who wants to order?
Ha ha ha!
现在，谁想订购？
哈哈哈！
[overlapping shouting]
[重叠的喊叫]
- Ha ha ha ha.
- Hey, Squidward.
- 哈哈哈哈。
- 嘿，章鱼哥。
Whoa, muscles.
哇，肌肉。
Hey, Squidward.
嘿，章鱼哥。
More layered pie.
更有层次感的馅饼。
Hey, Squidward.
- No, no, no!
嘿，章鱼哥。
- 不，不，不！
I think I'm going to be sick.
我想我会生病的。